<?xml version='1.0'?>

<project>
  <name>g2o: A General Framework for Graph Optimization</name>

  <author>
    <name>Rainer Kuemmerle</name>
    <url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~kuemmerl</url>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Giorgio Grisetti</name>
    <url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~grisetti</url>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Hauke Strasdat</name>
    <url>http://www.doc.ic.ac.uk/~strasdat/</url>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Kurt Konolige</name>
    <url>http://www.willowgarage.com/pages/people/kurt-konolige</url>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Wolfram Burgard</name>
    <url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~burgard/</url>
  </author>

  <briefdescription>
    g2o is an open-source C++ framework for optimizing graph-based nonlinear
    error functions.  g2o has been designed to be easily
    extensible to a wide range of problems and a new problem typically
    can be specified in a few lines of code.  The current implementation
    provides solutions to several variants of SLAM and BA.
  </briefdescription>

  <description>
    A wide range of problems in robotics as well as in computer-vision
    involve the minimization of a non-linear error function that can be
    represented as a graph. Typical instances are simultaneous
    localization and mapping (SLAM) or bundle adjustment (BA).  The
    overall goal in these problems is to find the configuration of
    parameters or state variables that maximally explain a set of
    measurements affected by Gaussian noise.  g2o is an open-source C++
    framework for such nonlinear least squares problems.  g2o has been
    designed to be easily extensible to a wide range of problems and a
    new problem typically can be specified in a few lines of code.  The
    current implementation provides solutions to several variants of SLAM
    and BA.  g2o offers a performance comparable to implementations of
    state-of-the-art approaches for the specific problems (02/2011).
  </description>

  <requirement>
    Developed under Linux (GCC). Tested under Linux, Windows (MinGW), and OS X.
    CMake is needed for building. Uses SuiteSparse if available, requires Qt4
    and libQGLViewer for the GUI. Includes a copy of Eigen3.
  </requirement>

  <map>Graphs (nodes and edge)</map>

  <input>
    Nodes and edges of a graph.
  </input>

  <logformat>
    A set of simple text messages to represent nodes and edges of the graph.
    Note that examples files are in the repository. See folder data.
  </logformat>

  <paper>
    <title>g2o: A General Framework for Graph Optimization</title>
    <authorlist>Rainer Kuemmerle, Giorgio Grisetti, Hauke Strasdat, Kurt Konolige, and Wolfram Burgard</authorlist>
    <publishedin>IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)</publishedin>
    <year>2011</year>
    <url>http://ais.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/publications/papers/kuemmerle11icra.pdf</url>
  </paper>

  <license>
    g2o is licenced under LGPL v3, whereas the g2o_viewer and g2o_incremental are licensed under GPL v3
  </license>

  <furthermore>
    C++ code, well-coded, compact, efficient.

    We thank Simon Julier for submitting patches to achieve compatibility with
    Mac OS X.

    The code of the OpenSLAM repository is a stable release. Please see
    <![CDATA[
    <a href="https://github.com/RainerKuemmerle/g2o" target="_blank">g2o on github</a>
    ]]>
    for our devel code.
    
  </furthermore>

</project>
